<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Francisco Rodrigues Pinto</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Francisco Rodrigues Pinto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Biological Networks</title>
      <link>/project/biological-networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/biological-networks/</guid>
      <description>As siblings might have a physical resemblance because they share a genetic background, diseases with similar symptoms are known to share affected genes. Cellular networks enable us to map genes that collaborate in certain functions and additionally, explore how are they are perturbed when some partner gene is missing. We aim to create tools that explore particular disease-related networks to identify which are the genes associated with the pathological origin of both diseases simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Modeling</title>
      <link>/project/mathematical-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mathematical-modeling/</guid>
      <description>Biological systems are complex. This complexity arises from their large number of diverse components and dense network of functional interactions between these components. One consequence of this complexity is that it is hard to predict the behaviour of biological systems in response to environmental or genetic perturbations.
In our group, we apply mathematical modeling to better understand biological systems in general and the multilayered regulation of gene expression in particular.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>